CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Jantsje Maria Mol, MSc.

Date of birth: 17-08-1990

Address: E7.30, Roetersstraat 11, 1018 WB Amsterdam

E-mail: j.m.mol@uva.nl
Website: www.jantsje.nl



I am a postdoctoral researcher at CREED, the Center for Research in Experimental Economics and political Decision making of the University of Amsterdam. My main interests are experimental economics and behavioral economics. Currently, I am working in the team of Shaul Shalvi on a project studying the importance of trust in the sharing economy.

I have a research master in Neuroeconomics from Maastricht University, with a particular focus on experimental economics and behavioral economics. My PhD supervisors are Wouter Botzen and Julia Blasch. My PhD project aimed to improve individual flood-preparedness by finding the determinants of individual decisions to invest in flood damage mitigation measures. I will defend my dissertation September 10th, 2021.

PUBLICATIONS

- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., Kranzler, E. C., and Kunreuther, H. C. (2021). All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners. *Behavioural Public Policy*. https://doi.org/10.1017/bpp.2021.17
- Morren, M., **Mol, J. M.**, Blasch, J. E., & Malek, Ž. (2021). Changing diets Testing the impact of knowledge and information nudges on sustainable dietary choices. Journal of *Environmental Psychology*, 75, 101610. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvp.2021.101610
- Bloemendaal, N., de Moel, H., **Mol, J. M**., Bosma, P. R. M., Polen, A. N., & Collins, J. M. (2021). Adequately reflecting the severity of tropical cyclones using the new Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale. *Environmental Research Letters*, *16*(1), 014048. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/abd131
- Mol, J.M., Botzen, W.J.W., Blasch, J.E., (2020). Behavioral motivations for self-insurance under different disaster risk insurance schemes. *Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization*, 180, 967-991, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2018.12.007
- **Mol, J. M**., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., and de Moel, H. (2020). Insights into flood risk misperceptions of homeowners in the Dutch river delta. *Risk Analysis*. https://doi.org/10.1111/risa.13479
- **Mol, J.M.**, van der Heijden, E.C.M., Potters, J.J.M., (2020). (Not) alone in the world: Cheating in the presence of a virtual observer. *Experimental Economics*. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10683-020-09644-0
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., and Blasch, J. E. (2020). Risk reduction in compulsory disaster insurance: Experimental evidence on moral hazard and financial incentives. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 84 (February 2020), 101500 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.101500
- Mol, J.M., (2019). Goggles in the lab: Economic experiments in immersive virtual environments. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 79(C), 155-164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.02.007

EDUCATION

2016 – 2021 PhD in behavioral economics of natural disaster risk

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Institute for Environmental Studies, department of Environmental Economics

Research visit Risk Management and Decision Processes Center, Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania

2014 – 2016 Master of Science in Cognitive & Clinical Neuroscience (Research Master)

Maastricht University

Track: Neuroeconomics.

Internship: Economic Experiments in Virtual Reality, Tilburg University, grade 9/10

2011 – 2014 Bachelor of Science

Tilburg University

Liberal Arts & Sciences. Major: Social Sciences. Graduated cum laude. Semester abroad at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

2016 – 2020 Environmental Economics (Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Teaching evaluations 2019: 4.22/5 Teaching evaluations 2018: 4.10/5

2018 – 2020 Statistics in R (practical, Master level), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Theses supervision

L. Braconi, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, MSc.
 A. Carvallo, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, MSc.
 A. Molenaar, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, BSc.

Lecturer

Dec 2019, 2020 Guest lecture on Experimental Economics, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*Mar 2018 OTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, *Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam*

Nov 2017 oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, Tilburg University

SEMINAR AND CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

2021 - ESA 2021 Global Around-The-Clock-Meetings (online)

2020 - ESA 2020 Global Around-The-Clock-Meetings (online)

- SABE 2020 (online)

- BIT (behavioral insights team) webinar (invited)

(for policy makers at the Ministry of Infrastructure and Water Management)

5th Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Heidelberg (poster)

2019 - Norms and Behavioral Change Workshop, University of Pennsylvania (poster)

BEEMA5, Villanova

- SPUDM, Amsterdam (poster) – Runner up Best Poster Award

WINK Nudging and Beyond, Utrecht University

European conference on risk perception, Université de Cergy Pontoise, Paris (invited)

2018 - CEAR/MRIC Behavioral Insurance Workshop, Munich

ESA World Meeting, Berlin

- 3rd Workshop on Experimental Economics for the Environment, Universität Hamburg

BEEC, Universidad del Rosario, Bogotá (poster)

2017 - VR for experimental economics workshop, RWTH Aachen (invited)

- TIBER Symposium, Tilburg University

- CREED lunch seminar, University of Amsterdam

SKILLS

Languages: Dutch: native

English: fluent

German, Spanish, French: basic

Software skills: R, Stata, SPSS, Microsoft Office, oTree, Adobe Creative Suite: advanced

MATLAB, HTML, Django, Python, JavaScript, ArcGIS Pro: intermediate